<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coefficients on easystats</title>
    <link>https://easystats.github.io/blog/tags/coefficients/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coefficients on easystats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://easystats.github.io/blog/tags/coefficients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News from the easystats-project: updated parameters and see packages.</title>
      <link>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_and_see_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_and_see_update/</guid>
      <description>New Features of the parameters and see PackageWe’re excited to announce some news from the easystats-project. Two packages were updated recently, the parameters-package and our visualization-toolbox, the see-package.
Before we start introducing some of the new features, we’d like to explain why you need the see-package to create plots for functions from other easystats packages. So, the see-package not only includes additional geoms, color scales and themes for ggplot2, but - maybe more important - also provides plot()-methods for many functions from the various easystats packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More models, more features: what&#39;s new in &#39;parameters&#39; 0.2.0</title>
      <link>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_v2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_v2/</guid>
      <description>The easystats project continues to grow, expanding its capabilities and features, and the parameters package 0.2.0 update is now on CRAN.
The primary goal of this package is to provide utilities for processing the parameters of various statistical models. It is useful for end-users as well as developers, as it is a lightweight and open-developed package.
The main function, model_parameters(), can be seen as an alternative to broom::tidy(). However, the package also include many more useful features, some of which are described in our improved documentation:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>parameters: a powerful and lightweight alternative to broom to describe your models&#39; coefficients</title>
      <link>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://easystats.github.io/blog/posts/parameters_presentation/</guid>
      <description>Okay, “an alternative to broom” might be a bit of an overstatement (at least for now…)
But the parameters package, finally on CRAN, already has some cool features!
parametersWe have recently decided to collaborate around the easystats project, a set of packages designed to make your life easier. This project encompasses several packages, devoted for instance to model internal access, Bayesian analysis, as well as indices of model performance and quality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>