<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on easystats</title>
    <link>/categories/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on easystats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatted correlation output with effect sizes</title>
      <link>/posts/04_report_correlation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/04_report_correlation/</guid>
      <description>One of the most time-consuming part of data analysis in science is the copy-pasting of specific values of some R output to a manuscript or a report. This task is frustrating, prone to errors, and increases the variability of statistical reporting. At the sime time, standardizing practices of what and how to report is crucial for reproducibility and clarity. The new report package was designed specifically to do this job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The end of errors in ANOVA reporting</title>
      <link>/posts/03_report_anova/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/03_report_anova/</guid>
      <description>Psychological science is still massively using analysis of variance (ANOVA). Despite its relative simplicity, I am very often confronted to errors in its reporting, for instance in student’s theses or manuscripts, or even published papers (See the excellent statcheck to quickly check the stats of a paper). Beyond the incomplete or just wrong reporting, one can find a tremendous amount of genuine errors (that could influence the results and their interpretation).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ressources and documentation to learn R</title>
      <link>/posts/02_ressources_learn_r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/02_ressources_learn_r/</guid>
      <description>GuidesHere are some links to get started with R:
R for DatascienceQuick-RDatacampEdX coursesStay tunedHere are some links of blogs and such to keep in touch with this evolving field:
r-bloggers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing R and easystats</title>
      <link>/posts/01_installingr/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/01_installingr/</guid>
      <description>Install R and R Studio  Go here: https://cloud.r-project.org/ Download the last version for your OS Install it Go here: https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/#download Download the right version for your OS Install it Start R studio  Install the easystats packages The easystats packages can be installed at once. If you wish to do so, enter one of the following in the console and press enter:
install.packages(&amp;quot;devtools&amp;quot;) library(devtools) devtools::install_github(&amp;quot;easystats/easystats&amp;quot;)  Once the packages are installed, you can load them all by putting the following at the beginning of every script:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>