<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>see on easystats</title>
    <link>/blog/tags/see/</link>
    <description>Recent content in see on easystats</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/tags/see/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>News from easystats: updated parameters and see packages.</title>
      <link>/blog/posts/parameters_and_see_update/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/posts/parameters_and_see_update/</guid>
      <description>New Features of the parameters and see PackageWe’re excited to announce some news from the easystats-project. Two packages were updated recently, the parameters-package and our visualization-toolbox, the see-package.
Before we start introducing some of the new features, we’d like to explain why you need the see-package to create plots for functions from other easystats packages. So, the see-package not only includes additional geoms, color scales and themes for ggplot2, but - maybe more important - also provides plot()-methods for many functions from the various easystats packages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#39;see&#39; package: beautiful figures for easystats</title>
      <link>/blog/posts/see_presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/posts/see_presentation/</guid>
      <description>The see packageWe have recently decided to collaborate around the new easystats project, a set of packages designed to make your life easier. This project encompasses several packages, devoted for instance to model access or Bayesian analysis, indices of model performance or visualisation.
Without further ado, please let us introduce the latest addition to the easyverse; the see package!
Essentially, see is the visualisation companion to other functions and packages in easystats.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>